<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>linux on The Computer Programmer, Nolleh</title>
    <link>https://nolleh.github.io/tags/linux/</link>
    <description>Recent content in linux on The Computer Programmer, Nolleh</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>ko-KR</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 11 Dec 2022 23:42:16 +0900</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://nolleh.github.io/tags/linux/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>2-2.linux History</title>
      <link>https://nolleh.github.io/linux/2.linux-philosophy-and-concepts/2.linux-history/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Dec 2022 23:42:16 +0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nolleh.github.io/linux/2.linux-philosophy-and-concepts/2.linux-history/</guid>
      <description>Linux History Overview initially developed on and for intel x86-based personal computers.
Linux History Linus Torvalds was a student in Helsinki, Finland, in 1991, when he started a project: writing his own operating system kernal. collected together and/or developed the other essential ingredients required to construct an entire operating system with his kernel at the center.
In 1992, Linux was re-licensed using General Public License (GPL) by GNU (a project of the Free Software Foundation or FSF, which promotes freely available software),</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2-1.introduction</title>
      <link>https://nolleh.github.io/linux/2.linux-philosophy-and-concepts/1.introduction/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Dec 2022 23:23:50 +0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nolleh.github.io/linux/2.linux-philosophy-and-concepts/1.introduction/</guid>
      <description>The Power of Linux Three Important Pieces of Context   Things change in Linux
Linux is contantly evolving. no matter how hard to make up-to-date as possible, Course &amp;lt;-/-&amp;gt; Linux
  We have repeated some things in the class meterial
  We have tried to avoid holy wars
there are many areas where there are strong preference disagreements in the Linux (and wider open source) community. examples include the best editor: emacs vs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>1-3.course Linux Requirements</title>
      <link>https://nolleh.github.io/linux/1.the-linux-foundation/3.course-linux-requirements/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Dec 2022 22:23:30 +0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nolleh.github.io/linux/1.the-linux-foundation/3.course-linux-requirements/</guid>
      <description>Course Software Requirements to fully benefit from this course, at least one linux distribution installed.
you will learn some more details about many available Linux distributions and the failies thy can be considered to belong to.
focus on 3 major distribution families.
Focus on Three Major Linux Distribution Families The Red Hat Family Red Hat Enterprise Linux (RHEL) heads the family that includes CentOS, CentOS Stream, Fedora and Oracle Linux.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>1-2.the Linux Foundation</title>
      <link>https://nolleh.github.io/linux/1.the-linux-foundation/2.the-linux-foundation/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Dec 2022 21:55:34 +0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nolleh.github.io/linux/1.the-linux-foundation/2.the-linux-foundation/</guid>
      <description>founded in 2000, supported by more than 1,000 members and is the world&amp;rsquo;s leading home for collaboration on open source software.
the foundation hosts hundreds of world&amp;rsquo;s most important open source projects including linux, kubernetes, Node.js, Hyperledger, ONAP&amp;hellip; and many more.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>1-1.Introduction</title>
      <link>https://nolleh.github.io/linux/1.the-linux-foundation/1.introduction/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Dec 2022 21:55:20 +0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nolleh.github.io/linux/1.the-linux-foundation/1.introduction/</guid>
      <description>we will learn&amp;hellip;
 linux foundation logistics of this online course choosing a linux distribution that&amp;rsquo;s right for you  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mac Cheat</title>
      <link>https://nolleh.github.io/env/mac-cheat/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Aug 2022 00:49:49 +0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nolleh.github.io/env/mac-cheat/</guid>
      <description>stackoverflow
유저그룹으로 권한 설정 example. brew
echo $(brew --prefix) echo $(groups $(whoami)) sudo dseditgroup -o edit -a $(whoami) -t user admin sudo chgrp -R admin $(brew --prefix) sudo chmod -R g+rwX $(brew --prefix) ls -lah $(brew --prefix) 순서대로,
 brew install path 확인하고 내 그룹 확인하고. 2에서 어드민 그룹에 없다면 어드민 그룹에 넣고 어드민 그룹으로 폴더 recursive 하게 소유권 변경 어드민 그룹에 있는 유저들에 대해 읽기,쓰기,실행 권한 부여 권한 확인   공식 문서 제안법 하나도 사용하지 않거나, 하나의 글로벌 brew 설치를 하고, 모든 다른 유저들에서 지역 버전을 사용하는것이 공식 제안 법.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
