<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Linux on The Computer Programmer, Nolleh</title>
    <link>https://nolleh.github.io/tags/linux/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Linux on The Computer Programmer, Nolleh</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>ko-KR</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 08 Jan 2023 15:32:36 +0900</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://nolleh.github.io/tags/linux/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>3-6.summary</title>
      <link>https://nolleh.github.io/linux/3.linux-basics-and-system-startup/6.summary/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Jan 2023 15:32:36 +0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nolleh.github.io/linux/3.linux-basics-and-system-startup/6.summary/</guid>
      <description>Summary Chapter Summary A partition is a logical part of the disk. A filesystem is a method of storing/finding files on a hard disk. By dividing the hard disk into partitions, data can be grouped and separated as needed. When a failure or mistake occurs, only the data in the affected partition will be damaged, while the data on the other partitions will likely survive. The boot process has multiple steps, starting with BIOS, which triggers the boot loader to start up the Linux kernel.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>3-5.linux Distribution Installation</title>
      <link>https://nolleh.github.io/linux/3.linux-basics-and-system-startup/5.linux-distribution-installation/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Jan 2023 14:15:48 +0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nolleh.github.io/linux/3.linux-basics-and-system-startup/5.linux-distribution-installation/</guid>
      <description>Linux Distribution Installation Choosing a Linux Distribution Questions to Ask when Choosing a Distribution What is the main function of the system (server or desktop)? What types of packages are important to the organization? For example, web server, word processing, etc. How much hard disk space is required and how much is available? For example, when installing Linux on an embedded device, space is usually constrained. How often are packages updated?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>3-4.linux Filesystem Basics</title>
      <link>https://nolleh.github.io/linux/3.linux-basics-and-system-startup/4.linux-filesystem-basics/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Jan 2023 13:44:22 +0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nolleh.github.io/linux/3.linux-basics-and-system-startup/4.linux-filesystem-basics/</guid>
      <description>3-4. Linux FileSystem Basics Linux FileSystem Conventional disk filesystems: ext3, ext4, XFS, Btrfs, JFS, NTFS, vfat, exfat, etc. Flash storage filesystems: ubifs, jffs2, yaffs, etc. Database filesystems Special purpose filesystems: procfs, sysfs, tmpfs, squashfs, debugfs, fuse, etc. Partitions and Filesystems A partition is physically contiguous section of disk, or what appears to be so in some advanced setups.
A filesystem is a method of storing/finding files on the hard disk (usually in a partition).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>3-3.kernel Init and Services</title>
      <link>https://nolleh.github.io/linux/3.linux-basics-and-system-startup/3.kernel-init-and-services/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Jan 2023 12:25:09 +0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nolleh.github.io/linux/3.linux-basics-and-system-startup/3.kernel-init-and-services/</guid>
      <description>Kernel, init and Services The Linux Kernel boot loader loads kernel and an initial RAM-based file system (initramfs) into memory, so it can be used directly by the kernel.
kernel loaded, it immediately initializes and configures the computer&amp;rsquo;s memory and also configures all the hardware attached to the system.
also load user space applications.
/sbin/init and Services Once kernel has set up all its hardware and mounted the root filesystem, the kernel runs sbin/init.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Shell</title>
      <link>https://nolleh.github.io/cheatsheet/shell/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2023 10:44:05 +0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nolleh.github.io/cheatsheet/shell/</guid>
      <description>Cheatsheet - Shell 쉘 커맨드들을 자주 까먹곤 해서 자주쓰는것 위주로 생각날때마다 하나씩 등록 예정.
Primitives if statement if [ 10 -gt 20 ]; then echo &amp;#39;gt&amp;#39;; else echo &amp;#39;lt&amp;#39;; fi; operator desc ! not true -n 문자열의 길이가 0보다 크다 -z 문자열의 길이가 0이다 = 문자열이 같다 -eq 정수가 같다 -gt 정수가 크다 -lt 정수가 작다 -d dir dir 디렉토리가 있다 -e file file 이 있다 for statement for file in *.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>3-2.the Boot Process</title>
      <link>https://nolleh.github.io/linux/3.linux-basics-and-system-startup/2.the-boot-process/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Dec 2022 22:21:34 +0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nolleh.github.io/linux/3.linux-basics-and-system-startup/2.the-boot-process/</guid>
      <description>The Boot Process The Linux boot process is the procedure for initializing the system.
from when the computer power is first swithced on until the user interface is fully operational.
having a good understanding of the steps in the boot process may help you with troubleshooting problems, as well as with tailoring the computer&amp;rsquo;s performance to your needs.
On the other hand, the boot process can be rather technical, and you can start using Linux without knowing all the details.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>3-1.introduction</title>
      <link>https://nolleh.github.io/linux/3.linux-basics-and-system-startup/1.introduction/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Dec 2022 22:19:08 +0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nolleh.github.io/linux/3.linux-basics-and-system-startup/1.introduction/</guid>
      <description>Learning Objectives Identify Linux filesystems. Identify the differences between partitions and filesystems Describe the boot process. Install Linux on a computer. </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2-6.chapter summary</title>
      <link>https://nolleh.github.io/linux/2.linux-philosophy-and-concepts/6.chapter-summary/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Dec 2022 22:02:31 +0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nolleh.github.io/linux/2.linux-philosophy-and-concepts/6.chapter-summary/</guid>
      <description>Chapter Summary Linux boroows heavily from UNIX operating system, with withch its creators were well-versed. LInux accesses many features and services through files and file-like objects. Linux is a fully multi-tasking, multi-user operating system, with built-in networking and service processes known as deamons. Linux is developed by a loose confederation of developers from all over the world, collaborating over the Internet,
with Linus Torvalds at th head. Technical sill and a desire to contriubte are the only qualifications for participating.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2-5.linux Distribution</title>
      <link>https://nolleh.github.io/linux/2.linux-philosophy-and-concepts/5.linux-distribution/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Dec 2022 21:38:28 +0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nolleh.github.io/linux/2.linux-philosophy-and-concepts/5.linux-distribution/</guid>
      <description>Linux Distribution Overview making sure that project works properly on the most widely used Linux distributions. To accomplish this, you need to learn amout the different components, services, and configurations associated with each distribution.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2-4.linux Terminology Overview</title>
      <link>https://nolleh.github.io/linux/2.linux-philosophy-and-concepts/4.linux-terminology-overview/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Dec 2022 21:27:09 +0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nolleh.github.io/linux/2.linux-philosophy-and-concepts/4.linux-terminology-overview/</guid>
      <description>Video: Linux Terminology Kernel: Glue between hardware and applications
Ditribution: Collection of software making up a Linux-based OS
BootLoader: Program that boots the operating system
Service: Program that runs as a background process
Filesystem: Method for sotring and organizing files
X window System: toolkit and protocol to build graphical subsystem
Shell: command line interpreter</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2-3.linux Philosophy</title>
      <link>https://nolleh.github.io/linux/2.linux-philosophy-and-concepts/3.linux-philosophy/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Dec 2022 14:37:33 +0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nolleh.github.io/linux/2.linux-philosophy-and-concepts/3.linux-philosophy/</guid>
      <description>Linux Philosophy Overview Linux is constantly enhanced and maintained by a network of developers from all over the world collaborating over the internet, with Linus Torvalds at the head.
Linux Philosophy Linux borrows heavily from the well-established UNIX operating system. it was written to be a free and open source system to be used in place of UNIX,
which at the time was designed for computers much more powerful than PCs and was quite expensive.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2-2.linux History</title>
      <link>https://nolleh.github.io/linux/2.linux-philosophy-and-concepts/2.linux-history/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Dec 2022 23:42:16 +0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nolleh.github.io/linux/2.linux-philosophy-and-concepts/2.linux-history/</guid>
      <description>Linux History Overview initially developed on and for intel x86-based personal computers.
Linux History Linus Torvalds was a student in Helsinki, Finland, in 1991, when he started a project: writing his own operating system kernal. collected together and/or developed the other essential ingredients required to construct an entire operating system with his kernel at the center.
In 1992, Linux was re-licensed using General Public License (GPL) by GNU (a project of the Free Software Foundation or FSF, which promotes freely available software),</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2-1.introduction</title>
      <link>https://nolleh.github.io/linux/2.linux-philosophy-and-concepts/1.introduction/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Dec 2022 23:23:50 +0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nolleh.github.io/linux/2.linux-philosophy-and-concepts/1.introduction/</guid>
      <description>The Power of Linux Three Important Pieces of Context Things change in Linux
Linux is contantly evolving. no matter how hard to make up-to-date as possible, Course &amp;lt;-/-&amp;gt; Linux
We have repeated some things in the class meterial
We have tried to avoid holy wars
there are many areas where there are strong preference disagreements in the Linux (and wider open source) community. examples include the best editor: emacs vs. vi; GNOME vs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>1-3.course Linux Requirements</title>
      <link>https://nolleh.github.io/linux/1.the-linux-foundation/3.course-linux-requirements/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Dec 2022 22:23:30 +0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nolleh.github.io/linux/1.the-linux-foundation/3.course-linux-requirements/</guid>
      <description>Course Software Requirements to fully benefit from this course, at least one linux distribution installed.
you will learn some more details about many available Linux distributions and the failies thy can be considered to belong to.
focus on 3 major distribution families.
Focus on Three Major Linux Distribution Families The Red Hat Family Red Hat Enterprise Linux (RHEL) heads the family that includes CentOS, CentOS Stream, Fedora and Oracle Linux.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>1-2.the Linux Foundation</title>
      <link>https://nolleh.github.io/linux/1.the-linux-foundation/2.the-linux-foundation/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Dec 2022 21:55:34 +0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nolleh.github.io/linux/1.the-linux-foundation/2.the-linux-foundation/</guid>
      <description>founded in 2000, supported by more than 1,000 members and is the world&amp;rsquo;s leading home for collaboration on open source software.
the foundation hosts hundreds of world&amp;rsquo;s most important open source projects including linux, kubernetes, Node.js, Hyperledger, ONAP&amp;hellip; and many more.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>1-1.Introduction</title>
      <link>https://nolleh.github.io/linux/1.the-linux-foundation/1.introduction/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Dec 2022 21:55:20 +0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nolleh.github.io/linux/1.the-linux-foundation/1.introduction/</guid>
      <description>we will learn&amp;hellip;
linux foundation logistics of this online course choosing a linux distribution that&amp;rsquo;s right for you </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mac 터미널에서 복수의 유저 사용하기</title>
      <link>https://nolleh.github.io/env/mac-terminal-multiple-user/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Aug 2022 00:49:49 +0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nolleh.github.io/env/mac-terminal-multiple-user/</guid>
      <description>복수의 유저 사용하기 맥터미널에서 복수의 유저를 사용하려면 몇가지 신경써야할 부분들이 생긴다.
home directory 가 분리 되어 있기 때문에 어떤 유저를 위해 설치한 데이터들은
다른 유저에서는 사용못할수도 있고 (그러는게 맞고, 그럴려고 격리한거니)
그러다보니 양쪽에서 같은 데이터를 설치해야하나 ?
혹은 서로 충돌이 난다거나 하는 불편함들이 생긴다.
대표적인 예로 brew 에서 이런 문제가 발생하는데,,
어떤 계정으로 설치한 패키지가 다른 계정에서 권한문제로 접근이 안되게 되면서 엉망이 된다.. (-_&amp;ndash;) dependency 가 있는 다른 패키지 들과도 맞물리게 되면서 내가 설치한 패키지가 아닌 패키지에 대해 데이터를 바꾸려고 하면서 권한 이슈로 연결 되는식.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
